<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Online Documents</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/</link><description>Recent content on Online Documents</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/010-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/010-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction # For those who are not familiar with the use of online documents such as these, this chapter introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;Static Site Generator&amp;rsquo; and gives a broad view of how it is used.
What is a ‘Static Site Generator’? # The document you are reading now is stored on a server. It has been delivered over the internet to a browser (Safari, Chrome or Firefox, for example) on your device, which may be a desktop PC (for the older readers), laptop, tablet or phone, for you to read.</description></item><item><title>Files &amp; Folders</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/015-files-and-folders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/015-files-and-folders/</guid><description>Files and Folders # Before getting into the detail of how to produce content for a document like this, it is important to understand how that content is organised into files and folders, and how these are used to generate the navigation menus. At this point, it is not necessary to understand the contents of the files: that will be covered in later chapters.
As an example, we will look at the organisation of files and folders in the version of Belfry Upkeep current at the time of writing.</description></item><item><title>Markdown</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/020-markdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/020-markdown/</guid><description>Markdown # The basic text input to Hugo is in a scripting language called Markdown, described fully in The Markdown Guide. This chapter provides a simple introduction – you will need to check the Markdown Guide for further options. Note that Markdown is text-based. It can be entered and edited using a code editor such as VS Code.
A warning and an apology for a rather long chapter. The use of Markdown is key to how Hugo works and you need to understand at least the basics at this stage.</description></item><item><title>Figures</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/030-images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/030-images/</guid><description>Figures # Figures (both pictures and video clips) could have been included in the Markdown chapter. But there are techical and style issues about how figures are treated in these online documents which merit a separate chapter.
Style for Figures and Captions # When work started on Belfry Upkeep - the first online document - our &amp;lsquo;model&amp;rsquo; was the Manual of Belfry Maintenance. This printed document does not reference figures by number, and figures have no captions.</description></item><item><title>Navigation Menus</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/040-navigation-menus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/040-navigation-menus/</guid><description>Navigation Menus # This chapter cover the navigation menus - the clickable list of document chapters on the left side of the screen and the clickable list of sections within the current chapter on the right side of the screen. (If you have a narrow browser window you will, of course need to click the menu bars at top left or right, as described in the Introduction).
In our view, this extensive hyperlinking removes the need for a conventional contents list or an index.</description></item><item><title>Publication</title><link>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/050-publication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cccbr.github.io/online-documents/docs/050-publication/</guid><description>Publishing a Document # The eventual aim for all CCCBR online documents is that the code will be held in a GitHub repository and published from there. The details of this will be described below. In developing an online document, however, you may find it convenient to work on your own device, generating the output on a local server. This is not essential but we have found it very useful and we will describe it first.</description></item></channel></rss>